<?xml version="1.0"?>
<configuration>
	<placeholders>
		<placeholder id="template_name">Salesforce to Netsuite Opportunity Migration</placeholder>
	</placeholders>
	<sections>
		<section id="use_case">
As a Salesforce admin I want to synchronize Opportunities from Salesforce to Netsuite.

This Anypoint Template should serve as a foundation for the process of migrating Opportunities from Salesforce instance to Netsuite, being able to specify filtering criteria and desired behaviour when an Opportunity already exists in the destination system. 

As implemented, this Anypoint Template leverages the [Batch Module](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/Batch+Processing).

Firstly the Anypoint Template will query Salesforce for all the existing Opportunities that match the filtering criteria. Account in Salesforce is represented by Customer in Netsuite. In the Saleforce it is possible to have an Opportunity without associated Account but in the Netsuite the Customer field is required in the Opportunity. The template will fetch and migrate only Opportunities with associated Account.

In the Process stage Customer is looked up by Opportunity Account name. If the Customer is found, the first one is selected to be used in Netsuite Opportunity. If it is not found, then new Customer is created with user defined subsidiary.

The last step of the Process stage will upsert the Opportunities into Netsuite based on the externalId field of the Netsuite Opportunity which should match the Salesforse Opportunity Id.

Finally during the On Complete stage the Anypoint Template will print output statistics data into the console and send a notification e-mail with the results of the batch execution. 
		</section>
		<section id="considerations">
<![CDATA[
To make this Anypoint Template run, there are certain preconditions that must be considered. All of them deal with the preparations in both, that must be made in order for all to run smoothly. **Failling to do so could lead to unexpected behavior of the template.**

For correct mapping of the Salesforce Opportunity *stage* to Netsuite Opportunity *status*, check DataWeave function stageToStatus() in *Opportunity To OPPORTUNITY* mapping. It should be checked if it contains correct data. The predefined data can be modified or new data can be added. If the Salesforce Opportunity *stage* is not found in the table the default value will be used. It can be specified in the *nets.opportunity.status.internalId* property.

The relevant data can be found this way:

+ **Salesforce**: Setup -> Customize -> Opportunities -> Fields -> Stage
+ **Netsuite**: Setup -> Sales -> Customer Statuses

Customer must be assigned to subsidiary. In this template, this is done statically and you must configure the property file with subsidiary *internalId* that is already in the system. You can find out this number by entering 'subsidiaries' 
into the NetSuite search field and selecting 'Page - Subsidiaries'. When you click on the 'View' next to the subsidiary chosen, you will see the ID in the URL line. Please, use this Id to populate *nets.subsidiaryId* property in the property file.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="run_it">
<![CDATA[

In any of the ways you would like to run this Anypoint Template this is an example of the output you'll see after hitting the HTTP endpoint:

<pre>
<h1>Batch Process initiated</h1>
<b>ID:</b>6eea3cc6-7c96-11e3-9a65-55f9f3ae584e<br/>
<b>Records to Be Processed: </b>9<br/>
<b>Start execution on: </b>Thu Apr 23 08:05:33 CEST 2015
</pre>
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="running_on_cloudhub">
<![CDATA[
Once your app is all set and started, supposing you choose as domain name `sfdc2netsOpportunityMigration` to trigger the use case you just need to hit `http://sfdc2netsOpportunityMigration.cloudhub.io/migrate` and report will be sent to the e-mails configured.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="running_on_standalone">
<![CDATA[
After this, to trigger the use case you just need to hit the local http endpoint with the port you configured in your file. If this is, for instance, `9090` then you should hit: `http://localhost:9090/migrate` and report will be sent to the e-mails configured.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="application_configuration">
		<![CDATA[
+ http.port `9090`
+ page.size `200`		

#### Salesforce Connector configuration

+ sfdc.a.username `bob.dylan@orga`
+ sfdc.a.password `DylanPassword123`
+ sfdc.a.securityToken `avsfwCUl7apQs56Xq2AKi3X`

#### Netsuite Connector configuration

+ nets.email `email@example.com`
+ nets.password `password`
+ nets.account `ABCDEF1234567`
+ nets.roleId `1`
+ nets.applicationId `77EBCBD6-AF9F-11E5-BF7F-FEFF819CDC9F`

#### Netsuite required fields

+ nets.customer.subsidiary.internalId `1`
+ nets.opportunity.status.internalId `10`

#### SMTP Services configuration

+ smtp.host `smtp.gmail.com`
+ smtp.port `587`
+ smtp.user `email%40example.com`
+ smtp.password `password`

#### Email Details

+ mail.from `batch.migrateOpportunities.migration%40mulesoft.com`
+ mail.to `your@email.com`
+ mail.subject `Batch Job Finished Report`
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="api_calls">
		<![CDATA[
Salesforce imposes limits on the number of API Calls that can be made. However, we make API call to Salesforce only once during migration, so this is not something to worry about.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="default_endpoints_xml">
		<![CDATA[
This is the file where you will find the inbound and outbound sides of your integration app.
This Anypoint Template has a [HTTP Listener Connector](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/HTTP+Listener+Connector) as the way to trigger the use case.

$H$H# Trigger Flow
**HTTP Listener Connector** - Start Report Generation

+ `${http.port}` is set as a property to be defined either on a property file or in CloudHub environment variables.
+ The path configured by default is `migrateopportunities` and you are free to change for the one you prefer.
+ The host name for all endpoints in your CloudHub configuration should be defined as `0.0.0.0`. CloudHub will then route requests from your application domain URL to the endpoint.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="default_business_logic_xml">
		<![CDATA[
Functional aspect of the Anypoint Template is implemented on this XML, directed by one flow responsible of excecuting the logic.
For the pourpose of this particular Anypoint Template the *mainFlow* just excecutes a [Batch Job](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/Batch+Processing). which handles all the logic of it:

1. Job execution is invoked from triggerFlow (endpoints.xml).
2. During the Process stage, each Opportunity will be filtered based on specified criteria. 
3. Account associated with Salesforce Opportunity is migrated to Customer associated with Opportunity in Netsuite. The matching is performed by querying a Netsuite instance for an entry with companyName same as the given Salesforce Account name.
4. The next step will insert a new Opportunity record into the Netsuite instance if there was none found in the previous step or update the existing one.
5. The final step will be sending execution report with statistics to e-mail adresses set.


]]>
		</section>
	</sections>
</configuration>